Allan Marquand Papers, 1858-1951 (bulk 1878-1950): Finding Aid C0269
Manuscripts Division
- Series 8: Papers of Others, 1875-1950; 17 boxes
  - Subseries 8A: Eleanor Cross Marquand, 1887-1952; 15 boxes
    - Garden Club of America and Garden Club of Princeton, 1922-1947 July; 2 boxes
      - Garden Club of America, 1922; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 2)
        photograph of Medal of Honor, awarded to Charles Sprague Sargent
      - Garden Clubs of America, 1929; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 3)
        Philadelphia, Wilmington
      - Garden Club of America, 1927 November-1939 November; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 4)
        miscellaneous bulletins
      - Garden Club of America, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 5)
        miscellaneous
      - Garden Club of Princeton, undated; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 6)
        book exhibitions, degree of fellow to Eleanor C. Marquand
    - Herbert Hoover, 1920 April-June; 1 box (Box 45)
      including correspondence
    - National Child Labor Committee, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Princeton University Library, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Princeton University, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - World War I, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - World War II, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 46, Folder 5)
      including the Committee to Defend America (with correspondence)
    - Printed Matter (Miscellaneous), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Printed Matter (Professional), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Journals, Booklets, Pamphlets, etc., undated; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 8B: Henry Gurdon Marquand, 1883-1900; 1 box
    Consists of the papers of Henry Gurdon Marquand, including correspondence, invoices, printed matter, and clippings.
    - Correspondence, 1883-1900; 1 box
      - Thomas Agnew & Sons, 1899; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Alexander, James W, 1900; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Alma-Tadema, Lawrence, Sir, 1884-1889; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Cleveland, Grover, 1891; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - "Mr. Helbig", 1888-1895; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - "Mr. Hunt", 1886; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - "Janitor of Metropolitan Museum", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 7)
      - Leighton, John, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 8)
      - Marquand, Allan, undated; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 9)
      - Ortiz, A, 1889; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 10)
      - Ready, William Talbot, undated; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 11)
      - Rhinelander, T. W, 1891; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 12)
      - Robinson, John Charles, Sir, 1891-1895; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 13)
      - Sedelmeyer, 1888; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 14)
      - Sloane, William Milligan, 1883; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 15)
      - Ward, Humphrey, 1899-1895; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 16)
      - Wigzell, John J, 1889; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 17)
      - "Lily", undated; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - Invoices, 1889-1890; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - "The Marquand Residence", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - Memorial Resolutions, dates not examined; 3 folders (Box 48, Folder 21-23)
      American Fine Arts Society, Metropolitan Museum of Art, Redwood Library, Newport, Rhode Island
    - Miscellaneous Printed Matter, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 24)
    - Press Clippings, undated; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 25)
    - The Princeton Review, 1884 March; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 26)
      "The Tariff on Works of Art"
    - Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 27)
  - Subseries 8C: Others, 1858-1940; 1 box
    Consists of some manuscripts, correspondence, documents, and printed matter of persons other than Allan, Eleanor Cross, and Henry Gurdon Marquand.
    Arranged alphabetically within forms/genres: manuscripts, correspondence, documents, and printed matter.
    - Manuscripts, 1887-1937; 1 box
      - "In the year of 1836...," Pierce Connelly, 1887; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - "The Origin of the Gothic Style," Thornton Floyd Turner, 1888; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - "Trees of the Bible," Walter M. Rankin, undated; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - Zur Lipsanothek von Brescia, Richard Delbrueck, 1937; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1875-1940; 1 box
      - Bagneti, Piers, 1920; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 6)
        ALS to "Sig. Mather"
      - Barringer, Rufus, 1886; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 7)
        ALS to James McCosh
      - Brown, William G, 1902; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 8)
        1 ALS to Woodrow Wilson, 1 ALS to "Mr. Maynard"
      - Condit, R. A, 1886; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 9)
        ALS to W. C. Prime
      - Cook, Walter W. S, 1920; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 10)
        ALS to "Dear Chandler"
      - Danske Museum of Decorative Arts, 1920; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 11)
        ALS to "Princeton University"
      - Edgell, George Harold, 1910; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 12)
        ALS to "Mr. Mather"
      - Gilmore, George W, 1922; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 13)
        TLS to John G. Hibben
      - Hall, I, 1875; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 14)
        ALS to James C. Stuart
      - Jason, Harold, 1902; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 15)
        ALS to "Mr. Carter"
      - Keyes, Homer Eaton, 1911; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 16)
        ALS to Frank Jewett Mather
      - Loeb, James, 1909; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 17)
        TLS to Francis W. Kelsey
      - Marconi, Guglielmo, 1902; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 18)
        TLS to J. Bottomley
      - Miller, J. Craig, undated; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 19)
        ALS to "Der Will"
      - Moray, T. C, 1886; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 20)
        TLS to Moses Taylor Pyne
      - Morey, Charles Rufus, 1922; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 21)
        TLS to Frank Jewett Mather, Jr.
      - O'Connor, Robert Barnard, 1919; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 22)
        ALS to "Dean West"
      - Sims, C. N. (Charles N.), 1887; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 23)
      - Thayer, Thatcher, 1877; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 24)
        ALS to "Rev. Prof. LeFron"
      - Wendell, Barrett, 1902; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 25)
        ALS to "Dr. Van Dyke"
      - Unidentified, 1940; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 26)
        ALS to Donald Egbert (Xerox)
    - Documents, 1858-1886; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 27)
      certificates granting honorary membership for J. S. Grandpierre in the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions
    - Printed Matter, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 28)
      Poems of Henry Marquand (brother of Allan Marquand), Nos. 43 and 47 of 100 copies
    - Miscellaneous Printed Matter, undated; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 29)